=======================

Privacy Policy
==============

**Welcome to Ticksy Privacy Policy**
------------------------------------

### 1\. Introduction

We, Ticksy, take the protection of your personal data very seriously and strictly adhere to the rules laid out by data protection laws and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR-EU and GDPR-UK).

This privacy notice gives you information on how we collect and process your personal data through your use of this site and any data you may provide if you contact us regarding our products and services.

Our appointed Data Protection Officer (DPO) is responsible for monitoring and providing guidance with our GDPR status. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact us using the contact information in section 15 of this privacy notice.

### 2\. Why we Collect your personal information

We collect your personal data for one of the following purposes:  
To fulfil an order, or take steps linked to an order: in particular, in facilitating and processing transactions that take place on the site.

Where this is necessary for purposes which are in our, or third parties’ legitimate interests. These interests include:

* Providing you with services described on the site.
* Verifying your identity when you sign into our site.
* Responding to support tickets and helping facilitate the resolution of any disputes.
* Updating you with operational news and information about our site and services e.g., to notify you about changes to our site, website disruptions or security updates.
* Carrying out technical analysis to determine how to improve the site and services we provide.
* Monitoring activities on the site e.g., to identify potential fraudulent activity or to ensure compliance with the terms that apply to the site.
* Managing our relationship with you e.g., by responding to your comments or queries submitted to us on the site or asking for your feedback or whether you want to participate in a survey.
* Managing our legal and operational affairs (including managing risks relating to content and fraud maters).
* Training Ticksy staff about how to best serve our use community.
* Improving our products and services.
* Providing general administrative and performance functions and activities.

Where you give us consent:

* Providing you with marketing information about products and services which we feel may interest you.
* Customising our services and website, like advertising that appear on the site – where this involves the use of cookies or similar technologies – in order to provide a more personalised experience.
* For purposes which are required by law.
* For the purposes of responding to requests by government, a court of law, or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.

### 3\. Lawful Basis Of Processing Information

We only collect and use personal information about you when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we use it where:

* The data subject (you) has given consent to the processing activity taking place.
* If the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract
* If the processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the controller is subject
* If the processing in necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interest pursed by us or our partners.

Where legitimate interest is identified as a lawful basis, we will undertake a legitimate interest assessment which is a three-part test covering:

**The purpose test** – to identify the legitimate interest

**Necessity test** – to consider if the processing is necessary for the purpose identified

**Balancing test** – considering the individual’s interests, rights or freedoms and whether these override the legitimate interests identified.

### 4\. What Information we collect and where from

We collect personal information from you, for example, if you register to our website, request product information, call us or use any of our services. We collect personal information directly when you provide it to us, automatically as you navigate through the Sites, or through other people when you use services associated with the Sites.

We collect your personal information when you provide it to us when you complete membership registration and buy or provide items or services on our Sites, subscribe to a newsletter, email list, submit feedback, enter a contest, fill out a survey, or send us a communication.  
Although we generally collect personal information directly from you, on occasion, we also collect certain categories of personal information about you from other sources. In particular:

* financial and/or transaction details from payment providers located in the US, Malta and UK in order to process a transaction.
* other third-party sources/ and or partners from US or UK, whereby we receive additional information about you (to the extent permitted by applicable law), such as demographic data or fraud detection information, and combine it with information we have about you. For example, fraud warnings from service providers like the Kount fraud prevention system we use.

The categories of personal information that we may collect, store and use about you include:

* Name, address, telephone number, email.
* IP address
* Payment agent details.
* Tax information.
* Photos.
* Item descriptions, support queries, forum comments.

### 5\. How Long we Keep Information For

We ensure that your personal data is only retained for the period that we need it for, or in accordance with laws, regulations and professional obligations that we are subject to. All personal information collect has a defined retention period, which is in-line with our retention policy. If you would like to find out how long your information is being retained, please see “additional information”, section 16 of this policy.

### 6\. Security of personal information

We take the responsibility for protecting your privacy very seriously and we will ensure your data is secured in accordance with our obligations under the Data Protection laws. We have in place technical and organisational measures to ensure personal information is secured and to prevent your personal data from being accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. We have in place a robust access control policy which limits access to your personal data to those employees, contractors and other third parties who only have a business need to know. The processing of your personal data will only take place subject to our instruction.

We have policies and procedures to handle any potential data security breaches and data subjects, third parties and any applicable regulators will be notified where we are legally required to do so.

We store personal information on secure servers that are managed by us and our service providers, and occasionally hard copy files that are kept in a secure location in the US. Personal information that we store or transmit is protected by security and access controls, including username and password authentication, two-factor authentication, and data encryption where appropriate.

We have ensured that all employees have had information security and data protection training. If you would like more details of the security we have in place, please see “additional information”, section 16 of this policy.

### 7\. Children’s information

We do not knowingly collect information on children. If we have collected personal information on a child, please contact us immediately using the details in section 15, so we can remove this information without any undue delay.

### 8\. Your individual rights

In this Section, we have summarised the rights that you have under General Data Protection Regulation. Some of the rights are complex, and not all the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Your principal rights under General Data Protection Regulation are:

* Right to Object
* Right of Access
* Right to be informed
* Right to Rectification
* Right to Erasure
* Right to Restrict Processing
* Right to Data Portability

* The right to object  
    You can exercise this right if
    
    * Processing relies on legitimate interest
    * Processing is for scientific or historical research
    * Processing includes automated decision making and profiling
    * Processing is for direct marketing purposes
* The right of access
    * You or any third party acting on your behalf with your authority may request a copy of the personal data we hold about you without charge.
    * We will ask to verify your identity or request evidence from the third party that they are acting on your behalf before releasing any personal data we hold about you.
* The right to be informed
    * We are required, to provide clear and transparent information to you about how we process your personal data. This privacy notice addresses this right.
* The right of rectification
    * If you believe the personal data we hold about you is incorrect or incomplete you have the right to correct this and you may exercise this right along with the right to restrict processing until these corrections are made.
* The right to erasure
    * If there is no legal basis or legitimate reason for processing your personal data, you may request that we erase it.
* The right to restrict processing
    * You may ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data. This means we will still hold it but not process it. This is a conditional right which may only be exercised when:
    * Processing is unlawful
    * We no longer need the personal data, but it is required for a legal process
    * You have exercised your right to object to processing and require processing to be halted while a decision on the request to object is made.
    * If you are exercising your right to rectification
* The right to data portability
    * You can request that your personal data is transferred to another controller or processor in a machine-readable format if:
    * Processing is based on consent
    * Processing is by automated means (i.e., not paper based)
    * Processing is necessary for the fulfilment of a contractual obligation

If you have any question about these rights, please see “additional information”, section 17 of this policy.

### 9\. Consent

Where you have given consent for processing, or explicit consent in relation to the processing of special category data, you have the right to withdraw this consent at any time, but this will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

### 10\. Failure To Provide Personal Information

Where we need to collect personal data by law or in order to process your instructions or perform a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to carry out your instructions or perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you. In this case, we may have to cancel our engagement or contract you have with us, but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

### 11\. Cookies

When you visit our website, there are certain information recorded which are generally anonymous information and do not reveal your identity. If you’re logged into your account, some of these information could be associated with your account. We’re talking about the following kinds of details:

* your IP address or proxy server IP address.
* the domain name you requested.
* the name of your internet service provider is sometimes captured depending on the configuration of your ISP connection.
* the date and time of your visit to the website.
* the length of your session.
* the pages which you have accessed.
* the number of times you access our site within any month.
* the file URL you look at and information relating to it.
* the website which referred you to our Sites.
* the operating system which your computer uses.

Where we have your consent to do so (e.g., if you have subscribed to one of our e-mail lists or have indicated that you are interested in receiving offers or information from us), we send you marketing communications by email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. You can ‘opt-out’ of such communications if you would prefer not to receive them in the future by using the “unsubscribe” facility provided in the communication itself.

Occasionally, we will use third party advertising companies to serve ads based on prior visits to our Sites.  For example, if you visit our Sites, you may later see an advert for our products and services when you visit a different Site.

### 12\. Automated Decision Making

Your personal data is not used in any automated decision making (a decision made solely by automated means without any human involvement) or profiling (automated processing of personal data to evaluate certain conditions about an individual).

Where we make an automated decision which has a legal or substantially similar effect, you have the right to speak to us and we may then review the decision, provide a more detailed explanation and assess if the automated decision was made correctly.

### 13\. Transfers To Third Parties

Ticksy may disclose your personal data, listed in section 4 to some third parties to help us deliver our services/products. All third parties are contractually bound to protect the personal data we provide to them. We may use several or all of the following categories of recipients:

* Business partners, suppliers, contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you
* Companies within our group where necessary for administrative purposes and to provide services to you
* Third parties that support us to provide products and services e.g., IT support, cloud-based software services, providers of telecommunications equipment)
* Marketing services providers
* Payment service providers
* Recruitment service providers
* Professional advisors e.g., lawyers, auditors
* Web analytics and search engine provider to ensure the continued improvement and optimisation of our website.

### 14\. Transfers Outside Of The EEA

In this section, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred and stored in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

We may share personal information to third parties outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). Any personal information transferred will only be processed on our instruction and we ensure that information security at the highest standard would be used to protect any personal information as required by the Data Protection laws.

Where personal data is transferred outside of the EEA to a country without an adequacy decision, we will ensure appropriate safeguards are in place prior to the transfer. These could include:

Standard Contractual Clauses

Binding Corporate Rules

An exception as defined in Article 49 of the EU GDPR

For more information about transfers and safeguarding measures, please contact us using the information in section 16.

### 15\. Right to complaint

We take any complaints about our collection and use of personal information very seriously.

If you think that our collection or use of personal information is unfair, misleading, or inappropriate, or have any other concern about our data processing, please raise this with us in the first instance.

To make a complaint, please contact us via email on [\[email protected\]](https://ticksy.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Alternatively, you can contact us:  
**By Phone:** +1-208-481-8061

Alternatively, you can make a complaint to the Supervisory Authority:

**By Post:  
**Data Protection Commission, 21 Fitzwilliam Square South, Dublin 2, DO2 RD28  
**By Website:** [Click Here](https://www.dataprotection.ie/)  
**By Email:**  
**By Phone:** 076 110 4800 / 057 868 4800

### 16\. Additional information

Your trust is important to us. That is why we are always available to talk with you at any time and answer any questions concerning how your data is processed. If you have any questions that could not be answered by this privacy policy or if you wish to receive more in-depth information about any topic within it, please contact our DPO and Compliance Team via email on [\[email protected\]](https://ticksy.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### 17\. Policy Review and Amendments

We keep this Policy under regular review. This Policy was last updated on 20/08/2021

We reserve the right to update this privacy notice at any time, and we will provide you with a new privacy notice when we make any substantial updates. We may also notify you in other ways from time to time about the processing of your personal information.

Copyright © 2010–2024 Ticksy

[Updates Blog](https://ticksy.com/updates/)  /  [Developer API](https://ticksy.com/api/)  /  [Privacy Policy](https://ticksy.com/privacy-policy/)

We use cookies to improve your online experience, analyse how our site is performing and offer personalised ads and content. Please let us know if you are happy to accept all cookies.

Got It! Manage Cookies

Close GDPR Cookie Settings

* Manage Cookies
* Necessary Cookies
* Third Party
* Cookie Policy

Manage Cookies

We use cookies to improve your online experience, analyse how our site is performing and offer personalised ads and content.

Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they as essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website.

We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website, and provide them with content and advertisements that are relevant to you. These cookies will only be stored on your browser with your consent, and you also have the option to opt-out of these cookies below.

Necessary Cookies

Necessary cookies are crucial for the basic functions of the website and the website will not work in its intended way without them. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable data.

Enable or Disable Cookies 

Third Party

Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.

Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with relevant ads and marketing campaigns. These cookies track visitors across websites and collect information to provide customized ads.

Enable or Disable Cookies 

Please enable Strictly Necessary Cookies first so that we can save your preferences!

Cookie Policy

More information about our [Cookie Policy](https://ticksy.com/privacy-policy/)

Enable All Save Changes
